AMAH Akan Daniel

Professional Job Profile

> +234 818 503 7181 | danielamahtoday@gmail.com

https://akanimohod19a.github.io/

A dedicated, detailed and capable demographic analyst with working knowledge of data collation, analysis and fieldwork, with experience in graduate-level demography/sociology research and preparing publications.

Based on my education and work experience, I have developed proficiency in questionnaire design, data analytics and machine learning as well as managing IT-related projects.

LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/2VjDzMG

Professional Job Experience

SurveyPlus LTD, Lekki Phase 1, Lagos

DATA ANALYST & OPERATIONS

Built and maintained an automated data reporting and exploration template in r-mark-down, that iteratively produced insights and context in an ongoing national field exercise.

Created interesting dashboards, that mined massive amounts of data from the field and survey participants to produce insights for survey sponsors.

Managed and Co-ordinated a national-wide exercise to on-board atleast 5,000 participants on an Application. Resolving technical issues with registered participants.

Established liasion with management to identify issues and use data to propose solutions for effective decision making.

Established new systems and procedures to improve the workflow in data and operational management.

Overhauled tedious processes by creating resolutional fixes using Python, R and Google Apps Script.

Built and developed relationships with business Clients and survey Respondents.

InsideSherpa for KPMG

Data Consultant (Virtual Internship)

Compiled and analyzed from a secondary data source.

Maintained a clear and coherent communication in written documents - text files and dashboards to understand data needs and report results.

Created clear reports that provided insights on business processes and maximisation of profits.

Performed other duties and followed through on work commitments.

Covens Lab, Akure, Ondo State

Data Analyst and Operations (Intern)

Provided technical and operaitonal support to facilitators during monthly data science classes.

Curated daily content and peculiar offerings on social media

Monitored conversion metrics on contents distrubuted on Twitter & Google My Business.

Intimated with science platforms to stay updated on current techniques and data science innovation.

Performed other duties as instructed

Research Assistant (Extra Curricular)

Conducted analytical and data research from which you will develop protypes and proof of concepts

Built and maintained an data pipeline from ODK to MS Excel to create exploratory analysis on target features that influenced Retirement Lifestyle among the aged in South-western Nigeria.

Performed other duties as instructed.

Dept. of Demography and Social Statistics, OAU, Ile-Ife, Osun State.

Data Consultant (Student Research)

Compiled and cleaned primary data for analysis using software packages: SPSS & STATA software analytical tools.

Evaluated the reliablity of compplimentary data sources and data gathering techniques and reinforce correction/standardization in analysis as well as for reference material. Produced and submitted a comprehensive report on Family Planning among fecund female adults in Ilesa-west LGA, Osun State.

Performed other duties and followed through on work commitments

Dec, 2020 - Present

September,2020

April,2019 – October,2020

June,2018 - October,2018

June,2017 - August,2017

SALEM SECONDARY SCHOOL, Ota, Ogun State

Teaching & Advice

 $\label{lem:computer} \mbox{Articulate and communicate basic - intermediate Computer Use to secondary school students.}$

Managed and optimized computer/research laboratory, as well as utilize for record-keeping and preparing examinations.

Scaling up basic competency in computing and programming, especially as regards application software(s)

Core Competencies

DATA ANALYTICS, FRAMEWORKS & SOFTWARE DESIGN	» Python » R	»	GOOGLE APPS SUITE GOOGLE APPS SCRIPTS	» »	Django Streamlit
	» R » STATA	» »	ODK	<i>»</i>	Dash, GraphQL
	» TABLEAU	»	Atlas TI (NLP)	»	Bootstrap
	» POWER BI	»	MySQL	»	Heroku CLI
	» MS OFFICE SUITE	»	Postgresql	»	Git and GitHub
RESEARCH & FIELD WORK	» Planning and Operations» IT Support» Requirement Analysis				
GRAPHICS DESIGN	» Adobe Creative Cloud » - Illustrator » - InDesign » - AfterEffects » Canva				

Publications



June 2019 - December, 2020

Tableau Public	<u>Dashboards</u> highlighting quintessential metrics through unique storytelling elements and visualizatio that explores how data can help drive social change and inclusion in Africa.	
R Markdown (.rmds)	<u>Publications:</u> showing automated reports, on EDAs and high-level Inferences on variety datasets.	
ML WebApps: Recommender System	er System Heart Failure Predictor: A recommender system on predicting the incidence of heart failure. Single Digits Peccapitar: A deep learning application to serve in real-time recognition of drawn image.	
ML WebApps: Computer Vision		
Google AddOn	Readability Guidelines Editor: A Google Docs add-on to keep your writing clear and readable on the web	
JOURNAL OF DEMOGRAPHY AND SOCIAL STATISTICS	"Evaluation of Household Age Data in the Nigerian Demographic and Health Survey, 2013.", Contributing Author. (In-View)	

Educational Background

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun State

BSc. in Demography and Social Statistics

Second Class Upper Division

Nigerian Navy Secondary School, Abeokuta, Ogun State

Senior Secondary School Certificate

Awards and Accreditations

Forage, for KPMG
Data Analytics Consulting Virtual

2020

2014 - 2018

2007 - 2013

National Youth Service Corps, Ondo State

Certificate for Distinguished Performance

2020

Conference Presentations

Dept. Demography and Social Statistics' Seminar Room.

"Mass Media: Assessing Fertility Rates with Family Planning, A case study of Ilesha, Osun State" 2016
"Evaluation of Household Age Data in the Nigerian Demographic and Health Survey, 2013." 2017

Language and Interest

Language: English and Yoruba

Interests: Reading

Referees

Referees will be furnished on request.